# miriam

## bellon

#### https://miriam-bellon.com

miriambellon@gmail.com 778 - 222 - 6405 Vancouver, BC

### skills

UX/UI Design User Research **User Testing** Prototyping Branding HTML/CSS Sass JavaScript React Node Video Edition Art Direction Advertising Digital Design Print Design Art Direction Copywriting

## tools

Figma

Illustration

Miro
XD
Sketch
GitHub
MySQL
MongoDB
Photoshop
Illustrator
InDesign
Premiere

## languages

Affter Effects

Spanish English French Experienced UX/UI Designer and Art Director with skills in User Research, Information Architecture, User Flow, digital and print design and front-end. Proficiency in branding, design and prototyping tools. Complementing my skills studying Web Dev.

## experience

**UX/UI** Designer - Freelance

Vancouver, BC | Mar 2021 - Present

Designed resposive app, wireframes and prototyping. Determined user flow and information architecture. Brands: FEVO.

#### **Graphic Designer - Circles Advertising**

Vancouver, BC | Jul - Oct 2020

Designed banners, brouchures and posters. Responsible of updating websites on Wordpress and coding. Assisted in filming a commercial. Brands: Tim Hortons, Executive Hotels, Hydra, TBC and Seaside Hotel.

#### Retail Sales Associate - PC Galore

Vancouver, BC | Apr - Aug 2019

Designed and developed a responsive company web, SEO management, product photography and copywriting for product posts. Helped clients in customer service and managed a FedEx post.

#### Web Designer Intern - Dream Sign

Alcobendas, ES | Feb 2019

Updated and coding websites on Wordpress. Designed banners, corporate presentations and icons. Brands: Renfe, Ahorramobel and aiEntreno.

#### Junior Art Director - Varenga

Madrid, ES | Feb - Jun 2018

Designed newsletters, broachures, posters, icons catalogs and banners for different companies. Retouched product images. Brands: Lantmannen, Carrier, UC3M, and Furuno.

#### **Graphic Designer - Carttec**

Alcobendas, ES | Aug 2017 - Feb 2018

In charge of the Marketing Department. Supervised SEO and new company web developing process. Updated the website on Wordpress, photographed and retouched products. Designed print items: factsheets, posters, banners and catalogs.

#### Freelance Art Director - Saatchi & Saatchi

Madrid, ES | Feb - Jun 2017

Supervised intern copywriter and art director. Copywriting and designed catalogs and posters. Determined art direction for Female Eurobasket photoshot. Designed digital design such as dinamic and static banners for the first electric company in the country, tv promotions, banners, storyboards, illustrations and style guides for the second biggest communications company in Spain. Brands: Toyota, Orange, Endesa, Samsung, Olay and GSK.

### Creative Intern - Grey Group

Madrid, ES | May - Nov 2016

Designed banners and newsletters and copywriting. Came up with creative concepts for campaigns. Attended to clients meetings with the Creative Executive Director. Brands: Domino's Pizza, Volvo, P&G, Fairy, Pantene and Real Madrid.

## education

Web & Mobile App Dev Diploma Cornerstone ICCC

Vancouver, BC | Aug 2020- Present

Full-Stack Designer WS Diploma Red Academy Vancouver, BC | Apr 2019- Mar 2020

Web Development Certificate IECEM

SS. Reyes, ES | Jul 2018- Feb 2019

Master's Creative Advertising Zink Project Madrid, ES | Oct 2015- Nov 2016

Bachelor's Advertising & Public Relations URJC

Madrid, ES | Sep 2011- Jul 2015

## other experience

Blog Contributor

Javascript in Plain English

Vancouver, BC | May 2021- Present

Writing articles about coding.

wireframing and prototyping.

UX/UI Researcher Volunteer
SIMBI Foundation
Vancouver, BC | Jul 2020- Present

UX/UI process for developing an accessible platform which helps students from a refugee camp improve their curriculum. User research, user flow, information architecture,